<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Communication on</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/</link><description>Recent content in Communication on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 19:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Asking Questions</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/asking-questions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 21:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/asking-questions/</guid><description>Definition: #
Questioning involves inquiry to construct models. Questioning to learn challenges, confirms or refutes hypotheses.
A context where I used this skill: #
I recently used &amp;ldquo;questions to learn&amp;rdquo; as part of task analysis. I interviewed end users to learn how they did their job. I built storyboard models of the usage scenarios. I asked users open ended questions to share their recent work experiences. During the interviews I asked clarifying questions to confirm definitions and ensure I had a common understanding with the interviewee.</description></item><item><title>Chartering</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/chartering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/chartering/</guid><description>Definition: #
A charter is a brief statement of what should be tested, how it should be tested, and problems that should be looked for, with the objective of having a clear mission for the session. The skill here, is to create a good charter quickly that both guides and plans the testing. The skill involves: thinking, planning, creativity, tests design, and likely writing.
A context where I used this skill: #
I was working in a testing group of 10 people on a pricing science web application.</description></item><item><title>Communicating Risk</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/communicating-risk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/communicating-risk/</guid><description>Definition: #
Eloquence combines several skills, but it includes knowing how to communicate to the audience in a way that it can be heard.
A context where I used this skill: #
Years ago doing programming on a project to generate insurance packets to customers. If we didn&amp;rsquo;t hit a magical deadline, the packets would be &amp;rsquo;late&amp;rsquo;, which had the perception, at least, of incredible pain &amp;ndash; people with insurance without the documentation of what the benefits were or legal proof.</description></item><item><title>Engaging the Audience</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/engaging-the-audience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 22:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/engaging-the-audience/</guid><description>Definition: #
Engaging the audience can be the difference between a great and a poor presentation, and involves not only the content, but many social skills too.
A context where I used this skill: #
Presenting is something fairly new to me, and something I&amp;rsquo;ve shied away from for many years due to my stammer. My fear was I would not engage the audience, in fact my fear was the exact opposite, I would make the audience disengaged as I spluttered my way through a presentation.</description></item><item><title>Managing Expectations</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/managing-expectations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/managing-expectations/</guid><description>Definition: #
Seeking to prevent disappointment by establishing in advance what can realistically be achieved or delivered by a project, undertaking, course of action, etc.
A context where I used this skill: #
Expectation Management is something I use 24 by 7 at work or life in general. But allow me to give a particular example that also highlights the cascading impact that expectations can have on product sales.
There was this Product development firm for which our team was performing &amp;ldquo;independent&amp;rdquo; testing.</description></item><item><title>Note Taking</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/note-taking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 19:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/note-taking/</guid><description>Definition: #
Note taking is the skill of accurately and effectively capturing information from some source(s).
A context where I used this skill: #
I use note taking often and in many different formats such as on paper, in text files residing on a computer, and in mind maps. I use this most frequently for trying to figure out how to reproduce difficult to reproduce issues in software. In one role, I was working on a native iPad app that was in its early stages and suffering from memory management issues that would result in crashing software.</description></item><item><title>Rhetoric</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/rhetoric/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/rhetoric/</guid><description>Definition: #
The ability to converse, written or verbally, in a powerful, persuasive way, particularly using examples and figures of speech to make a case.
A context where I used this skill: #
I was talking to a release manager at lunch. The project was, for the company, pretty big &amp;mdash; perhaps 200 person&amp;mdash;years and 24 calendar months, perhaps a bit larger. The team was trying scrum, but the &amp;rsquo;test&amp;rsquo; process was spiraling out of control, or at least, was in danger of spiraling.</description></item><item><title>Speaking About Testing To NonTesters</title><link>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/speaking-about-testing-to-nontesters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://associationforsoftwaretesting.github.io/whose/docs/communication/speaking-about-testing-to-nontesters/</guid><description>Definition: #
The ability to talk about testing with non-testers is a skill that enables tester to explain his ideas about testing in such a way that they are well received, regardless of what technical, philosophical or professional background the other person possesses.
A context where I used this skill: #
1. Stakeholder management #
There was a concerned raised by our users/business that defects reported by the QA team are more related to technical details of the build and not related to business use, or functionality related failures etc.</description></item></channel></rss>